Let's look now at some remote access methods
we have available for networking. The first one
will be for virtual private networks or VPNs for
short. By definition, a virtual private network is
a private network that uses a public network,
usually the internet, to transmit data from a
source to a destination. As I use the search bar
to search for and then open the VPN settings area,
I have a VPN connection set up just for
demonstration purposes. I will select it and
then Advanced options. Then, I will select Edit.
This example is a remote-to-site VPN connection
where I am using this to connect to a business
network. We have the name of the VPN connection,
the server address, and the type
of VPN, from which you can choose
which type of encrypted connection to use.
Then, a type of authentication is specified.
The other type of VPN connection
made is a site-to-site connection,
in which two businesses or two locations
within a network are connected to each other.